People are seeing day and night the
slaughter.
As I sit and do an an interview with
you, people are dying.
Bombs are exploding.
Who knows who's next? Will they target
our house?
Will they target a few streets
to the south? Will they target the
studio that I'm in?
Will they target
Who will they target? Who will they kill
next?
Hi, I'm John Kiriakou and welcome back
to Deep [music] Focus. Today, we're
revisiting a friend of ours,
Dr. Mohammad Marandi, who has long been
a friend of the show and a friend of
mine.
He is a professor of Orientalism and
English literature at the University of
Tehran.
He's speaking with us from Tehran, and
you can only imagine what the city is
like right now.
Mohammad, without any further preambles,
welcome to the show and thank you so
much for taking the time to be with us,
especially with everything that's
happening today.
Thank you very much for inviting me, and
it's always a pleasure being on your
show, John.
Thank you.
Mohammad, can you tell us what life is
like today in Tehran? It seems like you
have just relentless
missile strikes and and
ships firing from offshore and drones
and rockets.
What is day-to-day life like?
Well, because a lot of the targets are
civilian infrastructure, it is
pretty terrifying for a lot of people.
Uh we have
a large number of double-tap strikes
where they bomb a square or an apartment
building
or
some high-rise building and then when
people
go and rush to help
and first responders
are trying to
find survivors under under the rubble,
they strike again.
And this has happened
quite often.
One of my
friends was a witness to
Excuse me.
Was a witness to a double-tap attack
in Ferdowsi Square
in the city center of Tehran.
I spoke to a a journalist so a
journalist for Dropsite News
who's Iranian who lives in Iran
spoke to me or sent me a message and
told me
that um
he was in a square where the same thing
happened and they killed
20 people because
uh
they went to help the
the injured and they were trying to
find people under under the rubble.
So these sort of massacres are taking
place.
Uh
the uh
the United States and Israeli Air Force
they carry out uh carpet bombing. I
posted a a video
of one of their uh
strikes on a densely
populated neighborhood in Tehran.
It was
utterly vicious.
And um
so
uh
these are very dark times for humanity.
Of course it's an unprovoked war.
You wouldn't know that if you watch CNN
or BBC
or read the Guardian
or read in your Times or Breitbart or
Fox News.
You would uh think that somehow Iran
started this war. Even though this is
the third time
that the United States engages in war
with Iran.
The first time was of course
after it supported Saddam Hussein for
many years
and allowed it to obtain chemical
weapons through Germany.
Near the end of the war, they in order
to save Saddam cuz back then he was
their ally
uh they entered the war
uh destroyed Iran you attacked Iranian
naval ships, destroyed Iranian oil
platforms
and down the airliner killing 290
civilians.
The second time of course was 8-9 months
ago
when the Iranians and the Trump regime
were negotiating and he was
uh secretly conspiring to carry out a
blitzkrieg attack. And of course this
would be the third time that under the
cover of negotiations Trump was along
with Netanyahu planning an attack to
slaughter Iranian people.
But it if you look at the news any any
major news outlet in the West you would
never imagine that this is what's
happening the
unprovoked war where they murder leaders
where they murder scientists, where they
murder academics
where they murder families
slaughter entire
families wipe out entire apartment
blocks and they're doing it
simultaneously by the way in Lebanon as
well as we speak.
So it's a regional massacre.
But um
people are very steadfast and I'm
uh I'm quite stunned. I I I predicted
this. I believe this would be the case
but I didn't
quite
um
I didn't think it would be like this
every night.
And sometimes during the day, but every
night across the country people would
gather in cities
in tens of millions.
And in Tehran they gather not in one
place, but like in
20 or so places.
Each
hundreds or hundreds of thousands.
And during the first two nights where
these gatherings began
I posted the the ones in Tehran like
clip clips from different areas in
Tehran so people could understand what
if they put them together what a massive
crowd it would be.
And these people were under
bombardment.
The the
the Trump regime was bombing them.
They're firing missiles.
And you in some of the clips you could
see
the air anti
aircrafts or anti-missile systems
uh working.
But men and women stood their ground.
I found that to be extraordinary. I've
never seen such a thing before in my
life.
I have to agree with you and I want to
add something too that it is a it is a
war crime to strike civilian targets.
It's a war crime to rocket a school and
kill 160 children. It is a war crime to
sink
a a
a naval vessel
and then refuse to aid the survivors.
So this isn't just you know so many of
us yell about the Israelis.
>> that naval vessel was not armed. It had
gone to India
for a
>> That's right. uh a naval program that
different countries were involved.
And uh
they
effectively they were just men on the
ship.
And so they massacred them. They bombed
many hospitals.
On the first day they in Tehran they
bombed a
very large private hospital, the Gandhi
hospital.
They targeted the uh IVF clinic. So many
women won't be having babies.
They uh the whole hospital has been
emptied.
And it's private. I mean it's not I mean
no hospital is allowed to be You cannot
attack them, but it's not even state
owned or it's not owned by government.
And uh the massacre of the girls
on day one, there are two massacres on
day one. One is less noticed
because of the the fact that the
Trump regime targeted um
elementary school girls, killing 168 of
them and 10 or 20 I think 20 of their
teachers and
staff.
And well, you know, which we shouldn't
be surprised because uh
the Epstein class, they rape and murder
girls, so why not bomb them?
And then a few hours later they uh
bombed a gymnasium
where young women were playing
basketball. Where they were playing
volleyball.
And they massacred them, too.
But that that was just day one. I mean
it it's been going on every day and
today they among many other places they
bombed factories,
a pharmaceutical factory I hear they
bombed just about half an hour ago.
There was heavy bombing
about an an hour ago, half an hour ago.
And apparently they uh they they bombed
a pharmaceutical fan factory
in
in during those strikes.
They bombed the state national stadium,
the Olympic stadium in Iran
uh this morning.
The thing is that the thing is, John,
that they failed to destroy Iran's uh
military capabilities, the underground
missile cities, the underground drone
cities, the underground factories for
missiles and drones because they're deep
underground.
And I think uh you know, after
um
5 days and there's no letup on on the
Iranian side, they're very frustrated,
so they're taking it out increasingly on
ordinary Iranians. And so
we we're seeing more and more carpet
bombing rather than
uh it's becoming less targeted and more
carpet bombing.
And um
in in these strikes, we we we've uh
they've they bombed the national
emergency service building.
>> [clears throat]
>> They bombed the Red Crescent, the main
Red Crescent building. I mean, they're
just like during the riots a month ago
when their terrorists and their
uh trained rioters were slaughtering
people on the streets and slaughtering
police officers, if you recall back
then, they were targeting ambulances and
fire engines.
Now, back then,
fire trucks. Back then,
I was thinking, well, they are doing it
so that the buildings would burn and
that the injured would die.
But now I'm thinking that that that is
probably true true, but they were doing
it for today so that Iran would have a
a shortage of um
uh
ambulances and a shortage of equipment
to put out fires for during the wartime
period because they destroyed an awful
lot during those two 2 days of riots.
And in fact, they they just started uh
bombing specifically targeting uh police
stations with between 30 and 40 police
stations hit just in the last 24 hours.
Yes, they the police stations
that they hit they're just local police
stations that people
for neighborhoods.
So what they're trying to do by
destroying all the public
facilities and murdering public
employees
is to
destroy the fabric of society.
To break society apart. That's the
objective of the Trump regime.
And
it's like what they did in Gaza, the
same thing.
You know, the and of course the Western
media looks away just like back then. At
first they would make excuses.
They would blame
the victims. When the first hospital was
bombed they tried to pretend that the
resistance did it the second time, they
pretended that there were tunnels
underneath, then the third time, and the
fourth after three four times they just
said forget it. We'll just look away.
And it got so bad that if you recall
they went into one hospital
and unplugged the incubators
and let all those
infants die.
And no one in the Western media cared.
So this is where it is. This is where
things stand. And right now as we speak
they're doing the same in Lebanon.
They're about to carry out
carpet bombing in southern Beirut.
They've told everyone to leave the city
and you wouldn't know it if you watch
Western media. There's no outrage or
anything like that.
So
the West is indeed, John,
Epstein land.
It is it is the land of Epstein. It is
the land of the Epstein class.
And the the media is
owned and controlled by the Epstein
class. The state is owned and controlled
by the Epstein class. There are no laws.
There's no
There's no international law. They've
created the law of the jungle. This The
people who take little girls and do what
they do and did what they did, they are
the ones who are now slaughtering people
across the board in our region.
And the entire Western media,
they're they're like cheerleaders.
Mohammad, [snorts] I want to ask you
about about the supreme leader Ayatollah
Khamenei,
his assassination and the killing of his
virtually his entire family. I gave an
interview recently in which I equated
the assassination with
with killing the Pope. If you kill the
Pope, you're not going to bring down
Catholicism.
They'll just appoint a new Pope. If you
kill Ayatollah Khamenei, you're not
going to bring down Iranian society or
Shiism. They're just going to appoint
another another grand Ayatollah, another
supreme leader. Am I Am I missing
something as an analyst of the West and
of Western politics?
What What can you tell us about what the
American and Israeli goal might have
been in the killing of Ayatollah
Khamenei?
Well, first let me tell you a bit about
him
so that your viewers can know him a bit
better.
Because he's so
highly demonized.
Before the revolution, he he came from a
very poor family.
His father was a high-ranking religious
scholar.
He
went to jail six times, I think, or at
least he went to jail multiple times. I
think it was six times, but I I have to
check on that.
And he was tortured. He went He was
taken to the worst prison of all.
That was um in central Tehran
for the special prisoners.
And after the revolution he was the
youngest
leader of the revolutionary council.
But when the war started and Saddam
invaded Iran at the behest of the West
and the Soviet Union
he went to the war fronts even though he
had no military experience.
He had no military training.
And he so he went to the war front and
learned how to fight
while fighting.
Then he was assa- there was an
assassination attempt on him and he was
badly wounded his
right arm
uh his
he he he was not able to use it
afterwards.
And he was elected president.
And during the final months of the war
when the US entered the war on behalf of
its allies Saddam Hussein
and the war fronts became unstable
he quit Tehran as president and went to
the war fronts.
I saw him in the war fronts in the
southern fronts. That's where I saw him.
During the really most the
the real the
most difficult days of battle.
So and he was a target obviously he was
the president. But he was always on the
fronts and
he he was a person who had no fear.
And he was fluent in four languages
Persian, Arabic, Azari, and English.
Uh his uh
knowledge of literature, Persian,
Arabic, Azari, excellent.
The the most famous Azari poet
in contemporary history in the last few
hundred years Shahriar was his close
friend.
And
and he's from his father is from
Khamenei, which is an
Azeri city.
So,
his and his knowledge of English is
something that I'm and I'm aware of
personally.
Uh he has read novels in English. He's
read
uh
political material in English and uh
so he's he's a he's an intellectual. He
was an intellectual.
And on the day of his assassination, the
reason why he was at in his office, and
his office is beside his home,
is because during this whole period,
he was telling people that I the people
around him that he's not going to leave.
And he said that uh
many ordinary Iranians have nowhere to
go. They're struggling.
And so I'm not going anywhere.
And that's how it's been from the
beginning.
So, if you recall all those
childish stories that
uh these Persian media outlets that are
funded by the CIA and
Mossad and other intelligence agencies,
they spread rumors
about him.
Where they've taken him, where he's
hiding, the whole time.
The whole time,
he was at home and in his office.
There was no intelligence coup.
There was nothing. There was just a
a man who was not afraid to die
and who wouldn't leave because others
couldn't leave.
So, by killing him, by murdering him,
they made him a martyr.
The most important scholar in in Shia
Islam, the most important
religious
political figure in the entire
world.
Because he is not just the pope,
but he's also a political leader.
So,
his
followers and his supporters
are outraged
not just
for the insult and the aggression
against their
religious leader,
but also against
their political leader
whose
beliefs were
social justice
and emancipating the oppressed across
the world.
That's why he always supported
the resistance in Southern Africa
against the apartheid regime. That's why
he supported Cuba, even though it was a
communist state. He He He gave it
his support
even though Iran had its own problems,
its own economic problems. We had
maximum pressure sanctions, but we have
always been trying to support Cuba and
Venezuela and Nicaragua.
Why? Because
they were considered
to be oppressed under the the boots of
imperialism.
And the same is true with the
Palestinian cause.
And um
that that is basically his sin. At home,
his policy has always been He supported
the private sector, but his policy
cuz we've had different presidents with
very differing
economic and political views,
he would always insist
not to let the dispossessed
and the
uh financially vulnerable
uh
not to let them
uh suffer, to to to support them, to and
to strengthen them.
And um
and also um
one of the one
characteristic
of of his followers
is that
they're now becoming increasingly like
him.
Now they are prepared to die.
And this I think that probably the
reason why every night on the streets of
Tehran and other cities you see these
people standing there as they're being
bombed
and refraining from moving is because
they've been inspired
by him.
By the fact that he was not afraid
to die.
And so
I think that this is going to make it
even worse for the the Trump regime.
And uh
I think that uh the the steadfastness of
the Iranians
is going to
increase even
more than it would have if he was alive.
Significantly more.
And you know
John, I said this already to a couple of
people.
I've had three instances of people
contacting me, students
who told me that they were involved in
the riots. Not among they were not like
those who are the terrorists and
who are killing people
or who are burning down buildings, but
they were
you know, they were uh
they were excited and
they were foolish and
I I guess they did some stupid things. I
I didn't ask.
But um
these three people, I don't know them
well, but they they're from my faculty.
Couple of them I don't think I even I've
met before. I'm not quite sure.
I mean, I've been thinking about it
today
because I spoke about it a couple of
times and not I'm not quite sure. Um
you know, but in any case
two of them were quite emotional and um
they were saying, "What can we do? What
how can we make up for what we did?
How can we help?
And of course, I didn't know. I said,
like, go speak to this person or that
person and see what you can do.
But these young people who were
influenced by this Persian language
media apparatus, which is huge. I mean,
hundreds of television channels,
thousands of
uh
trolls. They have troll farms
everywhere. Just in Albania, thousands
are working in one troll farm. Tens of
tens of thousands of Iranians are on the
payroll.
And so,
a lot of these kids, these young kids
were influenced by this Persian language
media empire,
and who were influenced by these fake
narratives of the West loving human
rights and how all your problems belong
are because of your government and your
state and the Islamic Republic of Iran,
they saw with their own eyes what the
West does.
And uh 100 years of books
and uh philosophers teaching them in
class,
and political scientists
telling them about the s- crimes of the
United States and the Israeli regime,
it couldn't have had this effect.
People are seeing day and night the
slaughter.
As I sit and do an an interview with
you, people are dying.
Bombs are exploding.
Who knows who's next? Will they target
our house?
Will they target a few streets
to the south? Will they target the
studio that I'm in?
Will they target
Who will they target? Who will they kill
next?
And it's all just by chance. If you look
at
the places that they bombed,
often poor neighborhoods,
working-class neighborhoods,
middle-class neighborhoods, to the east
of the city, to the west of the city,
to the north of the city, to the south
of the city, everywhere.
They just slaughter.
And so, these young kids, except for I I
I'm sure some people are,
you know, they'll they'll they'll always
close their eyes to reality.
But, the decent ones, they've all seen
the reality of the United States.
And so, I think that the the United
States is going to have to wait another
decade or two
in order to uh
create another generation of
uh that has a a a
you know, substantial young set of
people who
believe their nonsense.
But, hopefully by then there will be no
more American empire. My uh my hope is
that it will end
in the in a very short period of time.
Mohammad, the administration here in the
United States is very clear that it
wants nothing short of regime change. At
the same time,
all Iran has to do to win is to survive.
How do you see this ending? Uh Donald
Trump said a couple of days ago that he
could see carrying out these attacks for
weeks. Well, attacks for weeks
isn't going to change anything. Iran is
an enormous country. It has 92 million
people. Its economy is diversified even
under sanctions. It's military is spread
out. It has a navy.
So, what does defeat for the West and
victory for Iran look like to an
Iranian?
I've been informed today by
a significant political figure that Iran
plans to continue this war until the
midterms
in the United States.
And uh
they will they are planning to
make the United States force the United
States to leave.
And the more this war escalates
the darker it becomes for US allies
across the region.
For the Arab family dictatorships in the
Persian Gulf
this
if it continues for much longer
they won't survive.
Remember, these are all dictatorships,
family dictatorships.
And the passport holders in these
um small entities
are sometimes 10 15% of the whole
population.
So in the Emirates you have 1.4 million
people
who are Emiratis, the rest, 10 million
or so, I guess
they are
they're
they're there.
But if the state
collapses, those slaves
and in the indentured servants and the
underclass
they had they may have something to say
about the future
of the Emirates
or Qatar
or Kuwait
and so on, and Bahrain.
So if this war lasts much longer
I don't see how these entities survive.
None of them have
a history, they don't they're not
they're not civilization states.
They don't have that sort of identity.
None of them have an ideology.
I mean, the Iranians are have Islam
and of course Shia Islam
has a particular
uh essence to it.
It supports the oppressed, it fights
against the oppressor.
It's
it's steadfast.
It has no fear of martyrdom
for the right cause, to support the
the the downtrodden.
And, you know, the you
this is is heavily influenced, of
course, by the prophet, his son-in-law,
and of course the the the martyrdom of
Imam Hussein
in Karbala, and his sister and the role
that his sister played.
I mean, if the American
elites had read something about Imam
Hussein,
uh they would have thought twice
before
taking on Iran and axis of resistance.
So, Iran will be steadfast, and they
will be bloody because the this Epstein
regime
is ruthless.
But, Iran will see this through.
And uh it will do what it takes.
And those proxies of the United States,
they will pay the price if the United
States keeps pushing, because they're
all complicit. They all host US bases.
US conspired against us through those
bases.
As we speak, they're using their
airspace.
As we speak,
they're using
their territory to fire missiles
from the ground, from the surface, to to
Iran.
So,
at the moment, the Iranians are focusing
on US assets and
assets linked to the US.
But,
it could get worse.
If the Iranians if for whatever reason
Iranians and the United States
get into if if the war between them
escalates,
there will be escalation in Iraq.
There will be escalation in Yemen.
And I think that you will see the
destruction of all the
tankers that are now stuck in the
Persian Gulf
and you will see the destruction of oil
and gas
installations.
And that will bring down the global
economy.
It will.
It will. The Strait of Hormuz being just
the start of of something like that.
Muhammad, the Washington Post
>> thing, John. Just one thing.
Iran is shutting the Strait of Hormuz
without destroying anything
to warn the Americans that this is what
is going to happen.
And Trump now says that he's going to
open the Strait of Hormuz.
He He doesn't have a chance in the world
to do it. His ships are far, far away
out of fear of Iranian missiles.
His planes are
far away.
That's why every time they bomb, they
have to refuel
and refuel again to get back
because of Iranian drones and missiles.
So, Iran is in is in full control.
There's nothing that the United States
can do about it.
And therefore, if push comes to shove
then you'll see the price of oil go to
what? $200, $250 a barrel?
And then when the markets crash
then everyone will be wondering who did
this.
And even
the MAGA people who
obviously have no moral principles
because
forever war is okay
hiding the Epstein files is okay
even shooting white people in the face
are okay.
All that's okay now.
But, uh, when they lose their jobs and
their factories, the factories that they
work at collapse
and the businesses
go bankrupt
and the price of gasoline becomes
unaffordable and they have no money to
pay for the gasoline,
I think they'll be
trying to figure out who's behind this.
Mohammad, The Washington Post asked a
rhetorical question on its front page
today. It said that
Russia and China are close friends of
Iran. Why aren't they helping?
First of all, are they not helping? And
second, can you comment on the current
relationship, whether it's diplomatic or
military, between Iran and Russia and
China?
There's no doubt that they are working
together, they're cooperating. Iran is
purchasing
weapons and doing business with them. I
I have no doubt. I don't know any
details,
but um the relationships between these
two countries are quite good.
And by the way, the Russians are
benefiting big time.
While Europe is paying extra prices a
higher price for energy, and the price
of gas is is going up even faster
uh because of Qatar
uh than the price of oil.
And this is really bad news for for
Western countries. I want to come right
back to that, but first we're going to
take a quick sponsor break. Thanks for
bearing with us.
Right now, we're watching two major
flashpoints unfold at the same time. The
takedown of El Mencho has thrown Mexico
into chaos, and US-Iran tensions are
escalating faster than anything we've
seen in years, all the way to full-out
war.
Here's what most people don't realize.
Every time global instability spikes
like this, one asset surges, gold. It
happened after 9/11. It happened during
the 2008 financial crisis. It happened
when Russia invaded Ukraine.
And it's happening again right now.
Well, there's a free report now called
the Global Crisis Playbook that lays out
exactly what's going on and what it
means for your for
It includes a step-by-step guide to
moving your retirement into physical
gold tax-free and penalty-free.
Plus a seven-point checklist experts say
every retiree should complete before the
next crisis hits.
I don't think you're going to hear this
on the evening news, but if you have a
401k, an IRA, or any retirement savings,
this is worth reading.
Simply go to johnlovesgold.com
and get your free copy. That's
johnlovesgold.com
or call toll-free 888-GOLD-053
to request your free copy.
Healthcare in this country is heavily
influenced by politics and large
pharmaceutical companies.
Politics change, access changes, and
medications that were once easy to get
can suddenly become harder to access.
That's why you need a place like All
Family Pharmacy. They're a licensed US
pharmacy focused on access and
transparency, not on politics.
In most areas of life, we prepare
financially, for security, for
emergencies. Preparing your medicine
cabinet should be no different. Instead
of getting a small supply and running
back every 30 days for refills, you can
order ahead and keep a 3-6 month supply
on hand.
I'm talking about antibiotics,
antivirals, ivermectin, mebendazole,
NAD+, blood pressure medications, and
more than 300 other prescription meds.
You choose what you need on their
website, a licensed doctor reviews your
request, prescribes it if appropriate,
and your medicine ships directly to your
door.
Healthcare shouldn't depend on politics
or on corporate gatekeeping.
Stock up today and save 10% on your
essential medications. What about the
nuclear program, Muhammad? And let me
preface this.
Uh the CIA said there was no nuclear
program. They said it twice in two
national intelligence estimates. The
consensus of all of the American uh
intelligence organizations was that
there was no nuclear program. Ayatollah
Khamenei issued a fatwa years ago
forbidding the development of a of a
nuclear weapon. Of course, the Israelis
worked hard to convince the world that
this was all a trick and of course there
was a a nuclear weapon and ever since
the 1990s Iran was only 6 months away
from developing this uh this nuclear
weapon. Well, a friend of mine made a
comment the other day that that struck
me as very important. We're not talking
today about North Korea. Why are we not
talking about North Korea? Because the
North Koreans have a nuclear weapon. And
no one dares challenge them.
So, perhaps Iran should have been
uh building a nuclear weapon. Or is that
analysis incorrect, do you think?
Well, you are correct. They've been
lying through their teeth about nuclear
weapons in Iran for decades.
And the evidence is there, but you
wouldn't know this if you watch Western
media.
Even Trump's opponents when it comes to
Iran,
they will tow the line.
Uh we saw during his State of the Union
address only time where all the seals
clapped together
and simultaneously was when he was
attacking Iran.
So,
uh Netanyahu has been saying it for uh
almost four decades.
The Israeli regime has been saying it
for more than four decades, the lie that
Iran is on the verge of a nuclear
weapon.
And we saw that during the war where
Saddam Hussein invaded Iran, where the
West gave him chemical weapons and I
survived two of those chemical attacks,
as you know.
Ayatollah Khomeini, the
Ayatollah Khamenei's predecessor,
gave a fatwa saying well, he said no, we
will not produce
chemical weapons.
And
of course the West tried to prevent Iran
from even purchasing gas masks.
But
then Ayatollah Khamenei gave his own
fatwa about nuclear weapons.
And the IAA has which has always been
in Iran and has for years carried out
very intrusive inspections, they have
never discovered any evidence that Iran
at any point
was attempting to build a nuclear weapon
at any point. Because the United States
says
the US intelligence agencies say since
and that at in 2003
the Ayatollah Khamenei gave a fatwa
and so
the
a move to build a nuclear weapon
stopped.
The IAA doesn't even confirm that.
And they're the ones on the ground.
There's never been any evidence. But at
least the US admits
US intelligence from 2003
to just a while back when Tulsi Gabbard
under oath said that Iran
is not developing nuclear weapons, it's
clear that Iran's program is peaceful.
So
Weitkopf is lying through his teeth.
The US Secretary of State is lying
through his teeth and Trump of course is
lying as well. And then in any case
Trump just 8-9 months ago said he
obliterated Iran's nuclear program. And
now Weitkopf is saying within a week
Iran can make a weapon.
It's obvious they're lying. This is 2003
all over again. The only difference is
that Iran is not Iraq.
Iran is not Libya. Iran isn't even
Vietnam.
And I think we've already seen that.
The Trump regime thought that this would
end in a day or two
and that Iran would be in chaos.
Well, we're approaching a week now.
And Iranian missiles and drones are
continue to hammer
and strike and Iranian
factories, underground factories
continue to produce.
And Iran still hasn't used its new
technology.
It's using old drones
and older missiles for them almost
exclusively.
And uh
in addition to that Iranians regional
allies
are still not
fully engaged.
So
ask if there is ask if there is Iran has
a lot of room for escalation.
What would that escalation look like?
I think the destruction of Would it and
and would it would it include the the
the use of Iran's uh hypersonic
missiles?
Which might not Iran has many uh wea-
weapons systems that they have not
revealed yet.
And by the way, with regards to nuclear
weapons, a lot of people in Iran argue
that.
And uh
two senior Iranian officials have sta-
said to advisors to the leader, one who
is now the chair of the Supreme National
Security Council, before he was the
chair, Dr. Larijani
said this and so did Dr. Kharrazi, who
was a foreign minister for eight years
under President Khatami. Both were
advisors to the leader.
And they both said, Dr. Kharrazi twice
and Dr. Larijani once
that um
if there is an existential threat to
Iran
then Iran's nuclear posture will change.
But look how patient Iran is.
And how
uh
you know, you know, with regards to this
it's not acting irresponsibly because a
nuclear weapon creates all sorts of
difficulties.
All these dictatorships around Iran,
Azerbaijan,
Aliyev is an unstable dictator.
In Kuwait, in Bahrain, in the Emirates,
none of these
Qatar, these are all family
dictatorships. None of them are
inherently stable regimes.
Then they'll all want nuclear weapons.
So that's one reason and of course
there's the moral issue which is the
main reason. That's why Iran never
produced chemical weapons. So we you
know, those who say that this
fatwa has no meaning out of their
ignorance of
of Shia Islam and of Islam.
Uh
at least they can look back in history
and see when we when the West was
gassing us, we refused to gas their
proxies.
That's the difference between us and the
West. Just as when they carry out
genocide in Gaza, we support the
Palestinians.
That's the difference between us. When
they strangle
Cuba, we support the Cubans.
When they take the
Venezuelan nation hostage, we support
the Venezuelan nation.
When it comes to morality, it's actually
the exact opposite of what the West
does.
Iran has always had the moral high
ground.
And Western propaganda
has always been
covering a reality that they are the
ones who have
no morality.
Zero morality.
And we saw it in Ayatollah Khamenei's
March.
We saw it
in the way in which
they conducted themselves and we see it
uh
when people are on the streets.
Iran
I know you know
a bit of quite a bit about Iran because
of people close to you.
Iran is a very highly educated country.
Yes, indeed.
Iran
it it there are more Persian language
media outlets working against Iran
than there are in Iran.
Billions of dollars a year are being
spent spent. Troll farms and and bots
and
billions of dollars. So Iran is always
hearing
the disinformation Iranians are always
hearing the disinformation.
Yet, despite all that, they come to the
streets and remain steadfast under
missile attacks.
That's the difference between Iranians
and Americans. Americans know nothing
about Iran.
They just hear what they They just know
what they hear on CNN or Fox News, which
is all rubbish. They're all controlled
by the Epstein class.
The same people who won't let us figure
out
who
Epstein's real contacts are all the
files that are hidden away and the
redacted information.
These are the That's the reality to
this. I think people are waking up to
this fact in the West. I'm I'm confident
in that. But the propaganda about Iran
is is is something much more difficult
to deal with because first of all,
people have been hearing this propaganda
for decades and second of all, Iran is
far away. It's this other.
So it's easier to demonize it. At home,
people are waking up. They saw Gaza.
They know about Zionism. But when it
comes to Iran,
it's a bit too difficult for them to
recognize that it's not what they
thought it was.
Mohammad, what about the prospects for
a widening of the conflict? We We hear
about
drones or or missile attacks against
against Cyprus or against Azerbaijan.
Um
whether they're true or not.
They they
Just in [snorts] terms of the propaganda
value it serves to to broaden the
conflict. Do you see it actually
broadening and what are the chances that
the Russians and the Chinese get more
involved?
Well, if you
if you
believe
Tucker Carlson's sources
and he is of course probably the most
well-connected journalist
in the world when it comes to US
politicians and the US military.
He says that
in Saudi Arabia and Qatar they arrested
Israeli Mossad agents who wanted to
plant bombs and carry out explosions.
So,
obviously the Israeli regime has a
vested interest in
creating chaos
and turning countries against one
another and that's what the empire has
done historically.
Divide and rule.
So,
that is and the Iranians have denied
firing
drones at Aramco and I think they also
said they did not fire anything at
Azerbaijan.
But but in any case if the war does
expand for whatever reason
these regimes won't last. Aliyev is a
dictator.
He'll fall.
Kuwait, Bahrain, Qatar
if this continues for a while
they won't survive.
At least the regimes won't survive.
And
the Emirates will never be the Emirates
again.
None of these entities will ever be and
this is huge loss for the United States
because these are key proxies of the
United States
which the United States milks.
They've been milking them since
they've discovered oil and gas.
So, the financial
punishment being inflicted on the United
States is not just the rise in the price
of oil.
It's the loss of this
purchasing power
that these regimes have
which helped the US economy.
And also
and I'm not an economist, so I should be
very careful not to
push this too far.
But also
it can be very dangerous for the
US dollar
because of the petrodollar.
Because this
the the dollar which is already in
serious trouble
is
is powerful largely because
of the fact that petroleum and natural
gas is bought and sold largely in
dollars.
So, there are lots of vulnerabilities
for the United States.
And these regimes, if they collapse
I think it'll be much worse for the
United States. And the United States
can't control this area. They can't
bring troops.
But they cannot win a war on the ground.
There's just too many There's Iraq.
There's the resistance in Iraq. There's
Yemen. These are big countries.
Yemen already fought a 7-week war.
And during those 7 weeks, every day we
were hearing from Trump that they're
winning. We're We're hearing from
Hegseth that they were wiping them all
out.
And then after 7 weeks, Trump said,
"They capitulated." And he walked away.
And they didn't capitulate. They won the
war. Yemen
and Saudi Allah or what they like to
call the Houthis in the West.
Which is, in my opinion, more of a
derogatory slur. But anyway
the point is that
the United States is no longer in any
position
to wage that sort of war and it will not
win that war.
And it will bring down the global
economy and it will bring down the US
economy
for multiple reasons.
So, yes, if the war expands
and Ayatollah Khamenei said it will be a
regional war and we're already seeing a
regional war. But the United but the
Iranians and their allies
are
not es- not escalating
swiftly.
They are they have they feel that time
is on their side
that they can escalate whenever they
feel the need to.
They control
the the the situation on the ground and
from the bombastic statements coming out
of the White House and
the Department of War
it's already clear that they're in
trouble.
Talking all sorts of nonsense and saying
I'm when Trump says I'm going to choose
the next leader.
The United States, you know, it's he's
living in fantasy land and I think it's
going to come crashing down
and I think Trump is going to be
devastated.
This is the end of his presidency.
Yeah, this is I I don't see how he gets
out of this. I really don't. Not with
any
any face or honor. I I just don't see
it. This was a terrible mistake.
This was
you know, one of the great crimes
against humanity in the modern era.
But since the United States and the
Israelis are used to it in Gaza and in
Lebanon
and in Syria
and in Libya, you know, it's not
surprising. But the problem is is that
they chose
the wrong enemy.
Mhm.
I think that's right. Well, Mohammad
Godspeed. I I hope that you are able you
and your family are able to remain safe.
All Iranians and
>> [music]
>> and I pray for a quick end to this
thing. Thank you so much for joining us.
Thank you very much. We do what we have
to do. It's whether
one survives or not, that's not really
relevant.
What's important is to do what's right.
And inshallah, hopefully we'll all do
what's right.
God be with you, Dad.
Thank you and with you.